<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Code & Quirks: Ramblings of a Weary Millennial Dev]]></title><description><![CDATA['Code & Quirks,' a digital refuge where the structured world of coding meets the chaotic musings of a millennial developer's mind.]]></description><link>https://shaunpezeshki.com</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 04:14:40 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Bridging Worlds: From Digital Agency to Public Service]]></title><description><![CDATA[Exploring the intersection of personal passions, cultural identity, and professional aspirations through a millennial developer's lens...]]></description><link>https://shaunpezeshki.com/2024/02/26/bridging-worlds-digital-agency-to-public-service</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://shaunpezeshki.com/2024/02/26/bridging-worlds-digital-agency-to-public-service</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://shaunpezeshki.com/static/7be6585ad624692413236fa621a603ed/e9253/representation-michigan.webp" length="0" type="image/webp"/><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
      style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 1600px; &quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/7be6585ad624692413236fa621a603ed/91298/representation-michigan.webp&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
    style=&quot;padding-bottom: 57.25%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/webp;base64,UklGRn4AAABXRUJQVlA4IHIAAABwBACdASoUAAsAPtFUo0uoJKMhsAgBABoJZQC06Yqg5dXtpq0Z+QgR3ZY4AAD+8d85LZdF+75lwBTcLJ+B/tsSNYYVpGh4rAhH35+tahmCznK9v2KTC57b5fGJynbRJrXah5Z3PrBbmgyS1rFwds/gAAA=&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
  &gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        alt=&quot;Map of Michigan with tech and asian influence&quot;
        title=&quot;&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/7be6585ad624692413236fa621a603ed/fad48/representation-michigan.webp&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/7be6585ad624692413236fa621a603ed/7f61c/representation-michigan.webp 400w,
/static/7be6585ad624692413236fa621a603ed/d00b9/representation-michigan.webp 800w,
/static/7be6585ad624692413236fa621a603ed/fad48/representation-michigan.webp 1600w,
/static/7be6585ad624692413236fa621a603ed/91298/representation-michigan.webp 1792w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px&quot;
        style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;
        loading=&quot;lazy&quot;
        decoding=&quot;async&quot;
      /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;prose prose-lg max-w-none&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    In the ever-changing landscape of my career journey, I find myself at yet another crossroad. The allure of a new opportunity beckons—this time, it&apos;s a role that, while not directly tied to my current professional realm, intrigues me with its promise of aligning my many passions with purposeful work. As I mull over a potential pivot to a Departmental Analyst position within Michigan&apos;s government, specifically focusing on the Michigan Asian Pacific American Affairs Commission (MAPAAC) administration, I&apos;m drawn to the unique convergence of public service, cultural advocacy, and the inherent drive to make a difference.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Where Passions Meet&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    At first glance, the transition from running a digital agency to a role steeped in public policy and community engagement might seem unconventional. Yet, the essence of what drives us often transcends the boundaries of our job descriptions. My journey as a millennial developer has always been about more than just code; it&apos;s been a quest for impact, a desire to weave the threads of my identity—Asian American, Middle Eastern American, LGBTQ+, entrepreneur—into a tapestry that not only tells my story but also uplifts others.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Digital Skills, Real-World Change&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    The skills in the digital realm are surprisingly adaptable to the nuanced world of public administration. Project management, analytical thinking, and a knack for distilling complex ideas into accessible solutions are just as vital in shaping policies and programs as they are in developing software. My experience in creating and nurturing a digital agency has endowed me with a strong understanding of how to build something from nothing, how to rally a team towards a common goal, and how to pivot when faced with unforeseen challenges—skills that are indispensable in public service.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Programming with Purpose&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    While the MAPAAC Administrator role may not involve coding in its traditional sense, the principles of problem-solving, innovation, and strategic thinking that underpin software development are integral to this position. Whether it&apos;s analyzing data to inform policy decisions, developing strategies to enhance community engagement, or crafting initiatives that promote inclusivity and diversity, the foundational skills acquired through coding can offer unique perspectives and approaches.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Blending Identities in Work&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    This potential career move is more than a professional transition; it&apos;s an opportunity to more deeply integrate the various facets of my identity into my work. The prospect of contributing to the betterment of the Asian Pacific American community in Michigan, advocating for LGBTQ+ rights, and leveraging my background in technology to drive initiatives forward is exhilarating. It represents a chance to not only grow personally and professionally but to also make a tangible difference in the lives of others.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Taking the Next Big Step&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    As I stand at the edge of this new journey, I&apos;m both excited and a bit nervous. But the more I think about it, the more I see how this role touches on things I really care about: new ideas, community, bringing people together, and making a difference. It reminds me that our work life is like a big, varied adventure, shaped by what we love, our experiences, and our wish to add to something bigger than just us.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt; 
    Thinking about this change, I realize that finding what really fulfills us isn&apos;t always a straight road. It&apos;s more like a journey with unexpected twists, big discoveries, and most of all, the courage to go after what truly matters to us. As I look forward to what&apos;s ahead, I&apos;m excited by the possibilities and the chance to see if this new path is the right fit for me, even if the role isn&apos;t exactly what I was looking for.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Navigating the Future: AI, Jobs, and the Millennial Conundrum]]></title><description><![CDATA[ In an era where AI's rapid evolution reshapes our job landscape, a 35-year-old millennial developer reflects on the future of work amidst tech layoffs, economic uncertainties, and the widening wealth gap...]]></description><link>https://shaunpezeshki.com/2024/02/21/navigating-the-future-ai-jobs-and-the-millennial-conundrum</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://shaunpezeshki.com/2024/02/21/navigating-the-future-ai-jobs-and-the-millennial-conundrum</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://shaunpezeshki.com/static/647a9bcde2f825ce7c8cf321115cf0c7/52890/future-ai.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
      style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 1500px; &quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/647a9bcde2f825ce7c8cf321115cf0c7/c58a3/future-ai.jpg&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
    style=&quot;padding-bottom: 57.25%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAALABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFwAAAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAMEAv/EABUBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEA/9oADAMBAAIQAxAAAAHNMzonFA//xAAZEAEBAQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAABAhEAEjL/2gAIAQEAAQUCknKc5J2aefm19f/EABcRAQADAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABESH/2gAIAQMBAT8BjFv/xAAXEQEAAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAREh/9oACAECAQE/AZ1T/8QAGxAAAgEFAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAADERAQIQM0H/2gAIAQEABj8CUFJt4axrP//EABsQAQADAQADAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEAESExQVGB/9oACAEBAAE/IfbfjJRFo05Oxb7G2OAVGipcWWuz/9oADAMBAAIAAwAAABAU/wD/xAAXEQADAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAUFR/9oACAEDAQE/ELDXD//EABcRAAMBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABQVH/2gAIAQIBAT8QkJ9P/8QAHBAAAgICAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAREAIUFRMXGx/9oACAEBAAE/EOkZCyOi4VDaDyyYazG2HkYZQtMwvtIW8znuiRP/2Q==&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
  &gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        alt=&quot;The future of AI and tech&quot;
        title=&quot;&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/647a9bcde2f825ce7c8cf321115cf0c7/c58a3/future-ai.jpg&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/647a9bcde2f825ce7c8cf321115cf0c7/066f9/future-ai.jpg 400w,
/static/647a9bcde2f825ce7c8cf321115cf0c7/4b190/future-ai.jpg 800w,
/static/647a9bcde2f825ce7c8cf321115cf0c7/c58a3/future-ai.jpg 1500w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1500px) 100vw, 1500px&quot;
        style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;
        loading=&quot;lazy&quot;
        decoding=&quot;async&quot;
      /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;prose prose-lg max-w-none&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    As we stand at the crossroads of an AI-driven era, the pace at which artificial intelligence evolves sends ripples through our professional lives, prompting both awe and anxiety. The question that looms large is: As AI continues to advance, what does the future hold for our jobs?
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;The Tech Layoff Wave&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Recent headlines are awash with news of tech layoffs, a stark reminder of the volatility in the sector many of us call home. Companies that once seemed invincible now face the daunting task of navigating through economic downturns, leading to job cuts that have left many of us pondering our future in this industry.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;The Economic Divide&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Amidst this turbulence, the economic landscape continues to shift, with inflation gnawing at the edges of our hard-earned salaries. The chasm between the wealthiest 1% and the rest widens, casting a shadow over the dream of a balanced society where hard work and innovation are rewarded.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Looking Ahead: Potential Outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    As we peer into the horizon, several potential outcomes emerge, painting a picture of what the future may hold:
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Rise of Gig Economy 2.0:&lt;/strong&gt; The gig economy, characterized by short-term contracts and freelance work, could evolve into a more dominant employment model. This shift could offer flexibility and a multitude of opportunities for those willing to adapt, though it may also lead to less job security and benefits.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Specialization and Continuous Learning:&lt;/strong&gt; As AI takes over routine tasks, there will be a growing demand for specialized skills that AI cannot easily replicate. Continuous learning and upskilling will become not just beneficial but essential for staying relevant in the job market.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Emergence of New Job Roles:&lt;/strong&gt; Just as the industrial revolution created jobs that were previously unimaginable, the AI revolution is likely to spawn new roles that we can&apos;t yet foresee. These roles will likely revolve around AI oversight, ethical considerations, and more creative and strategic positions that require a human touch.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Collaboration of Human and AI:&lt;/strong&gt; Rather than viewing AI as a threat, the future might hold a more collaborative relationship between humans and AI. This synergy could enhance our capabilities, making us more efficient and freeing us up to focus on complex problem-solving and innovative thinking.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    While the future may seem daunting, history has shown us that with change comes opportunity. By embracing the unknown with curiosity and resilience, we can navigate the evolving landscape, finding new ways to blend our unique human skills with the capabilities of AI. The future is not written in stone; it&apos;s up to us to carve out our path, leveraging the quirks of our millennial mindset to adapt, innovate, and thrive in the face of change.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    As we continue this journey together, I invite you to share your thoughts, fears, and hopes for the future. How do you see AI shaping our professional lives? What strategies are you considering to stay relevant in this new era? Let&apos;s embark on this exploration together, finding solace and strength in our shared experiences and diverse perspectives.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Embracing Uncertainty: Navigating the Whirlwind of Millennial Existence]]></title><description><![CDATA[Join me on a journey through the tumultuous landscape of a millennial's mind, where the chaos of life intersects with the order of coding...]]></description><link>https://shaunpezeshki.com/2024/02/20/embracing-uncertainty-millennial-existence</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://shaunpezeshki.com/2024/02/20/embracing-uncertainty-millennial-existence</guid><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://shaunpezeshki.com/static/bfc9ed303cfdb26115998aa826cbbe21/c8e72/millenial-tired.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
      style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 1600px; &quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/bfc9ed303cfdb26115998aa826cbbe21/fa60d/millenial-tired.png&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
    style=&quot;padding-bottom: 57.25%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABQAAAALCAIAAADwazoUAAAACXBIWXMAAAsTAAALEwEAmpwYAAAChUlEQVR42iWSW0/acBjG/RC73y73CZYlu98uTHazCYo6ztACLRQKlkMpClQEykmgnI+tFUGgLnOaiEyHZJunOJctJov7Drt10f2N9+8vz/P88k5IlPCczmQhyCCTYit18cN2V9wS2p06z7c67YPD/es/V5v9rjdAX/44b21uLoVjiN0l05imFNCEVAWrESvNJKu8EM+wQnuDLZVtbjJfKoUTKQfpGwz38uUKYieKtWoolmDLNXA8r0NA6j0MWxciyXQim1tlcxcXx0ejYbstiGKnXK2sZjJOr09nwWUa+B2E0NF4qcExaVYOm6UAlighxOEmKD8VXE6k0/libvdjX+yuHwx3voyHJ8efs3kWseJaIxqMMDWOW44lkmxeb3FMKfT3yXIYndcZXs/IIRTr9TZ2tvs/L09EsdWoF27//b36dVapFJKpuC/gd/qWPP7g4nLYiDvv4Rm1UaYxvHojfStX15rN92J7sLvF8TUTCt3d3tzd3Vz//i5wFa5ZyWRXCZKigiHU7kQdblB5AlQ3Ex5/OJpic7zA97obx18/xZPRR4+fYBg82O0yUXpdqJ+fHoHwfKkYTaUpesXmpqbBZmDcvOCZVukxpyeaSFRr5fFo7+x0bHMTJszkD1Lj0SDEhPu99prAcQIPvJodLpXRAvYCWK9FcYUBtXt92UKhyXMNru4J+A9H+421hhyGW53W02cvIDMWZqIEtRiIMBBmB68hebAt0xitLi/QQEcYvQXH3aRMA63E4laXZ1I6i3vI5y8nIcz27WSMOJxGG6FD8Tntw5Mo4Rm1QWmw4OSiLxQhqCWKpq0uMlsohuMJg9UOtgDJsXQad3uBJy1qm9Uap1WwRAH9B5vYYPpjUXC2AAAAAElFTkSuQmCC&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
  &gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        alt=&quot;The struggling millenial&quot;
        title=&quot;&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/bfc9ed303cfdb26115998aa826cbbe21/29007/millenial-tired.png&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/bfc9ed303cfdb26115998aa826cbbe21/e17e5/millenial-tired.png 400w,
/static/bfc9ed303cfdb26115998aa826cbbe21/5a190/millenial-tired.png 800w,
/static/bfc9ed303cfdb26115998aa826cbbe21/29007/millenial-tired.png 1600w,
/static/bfc9ed303cfdb26115998aa826cbbe21/fa60d/millenial-tired.png 1792w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px&quot;
        style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;
        loading=&quot;lazy&quot;
        decoding=&quot;async&quot;
      /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;prose prose-lg max-w-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to &apos;Code &amp; Quirks,&apos; where the digital world intertwines with the labyrinth of a millennial&apos;s thoughts. I&apos;m Shaun Pezeshki, your weary yet whimsical guide, navigating the twists and turns of existence in my 30s. Life in this decade feels like a perpetual second-guessing, a constant struggle to find purpose amidst the noise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;From Extrovert to Introvert&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my 20s, I was a social butterfly, flitting from one adventure to the next with boundless energy. But as the years passed, the pace slowed, and the once vibrant social scene faded into the background. Now, caught in the throes of a daily routine, I find myself longing for connection yet hesitant to step outside my comfort zone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Navigating Uncertainty&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The existential dread of not having it all figured out weighs heavy, manifesting in bouts of &apos;doom scrolling&apos; through endless feeds of curated perfection. Yet, amidst the chaos, there are moments of clarity, bursts of energy that propel me to articulate my thoughts, like crafting this very introduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Finding Peace Within&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without active outdoor hobbies to ground me, I find solace in introspection, grappling with the notion that life must adhere to a predefined script. But deep down, I understand that life is a messy, nonlinear journey, devoid of easy answers or clear-cut paths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Understanding Darkness&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One peculiar skill I&apos;ve honed over the years is empathizing with the darkest corners of human nature. Perhaps it stems from my own moments of doubt and disillusionment, a reminder that behind every facade lies a complex web of emotions and experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Let&apos;s Explore Together&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, join me as we delve into the intricacies of millennial existence, embracing the uncertainty and finding solace in the shared experiences of navigating this chaotic yet beautiful world. Together, we&apos;ll explore the intersections of tech, life, and the absurdities that make us uniquely human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>